君が見る夢は　古いインクで紙に書いた祈りのよう
小さなその手が　縋るものも　今はまだ何処にも無い
それでも君の行く道を
奇麗なものは奇麗なままで　守り続けたいと思うよ
空と水が星を染めて
淡く虹を描いて散って
眩しい夜　君が歌う
声は何処まで届くのだろう
憧れの住まう蒼い星のひかり
ただ僕らは恋をして
たったひとつの未来の為に
今の全て奏でてみる
飛び立つよ　まだ暗い空へ
一体どういう事か
What in the world has happened?
My granddaughter Asseylum is assassinated,
我が孫娘アセイラムが暗殺されて
and we go to war against Earth
without so much as a declaration?
宣戦布告すら無いまま地球と戦争
親善大使を手にかければどうなるか　分かっているはず
Surely they knew what would come of harming a goodwill ambassador.
So why?
なのになぜ
What is happening there outside my reach?
わしの知らぬ所で　何が起きておる
We are told the assassination was an act of terrorism.
暗殺者は　テロリストであると聞いております
では連合政府に敵意は無いのではないか
That would mean the UE harbors us no ill will.
地球に反ヴァース勢力が存在する事は明白
I am sure they realize that Earth is rife with anti-Vers sentiment.
For the assassination to succeed in spite of that suggests that security was deliberately lax.
にもかかわらず暗殺を許すとは
意図して護衛を怠ったとも考えられます
もしくは連合政府によるテロに見せかけた暗殺の可能性も
Her assassination may also have been perpetrated by the UE under the guise of a terrorist attack.
To what end?
何のために
姫様はアルドノアを呼び覚ます王族の血を引くもの
Her Highness' royal blood is capable
of stirring the power of Aldnoah to life.
その血筋はヴァースの力そのものであります
That bloodline is the very foundation
of the Empire's might.
It makes no sense.
解せぬ
連合政府に休戦を申し出よ　そして事実を明らかにせよ
Announce an armistice to the UE government.
Investigate and uncover the truth.
御意
Very well.
How goes the war, Count Cruhteo?
戦況は如何かな　クルーテオ伯爵
I am most pleased.
万事上首尾
We have occupied Tokyo and the surrounding cities,
東京及び周囲の都市は占拠を終え
アセイラム姫の眠る新芦原も既に我が手中
and Shin-awara, where Princess Asseylum fell,
has also been conquered.
それは大儀である
Excellent work.
Incidentally, where is Sir Trillram?
ときに　トリルラン卿は今いずこに
Is he still making a name for himself on the battlefield?
今も戦地で武勲を上げておるか
それが…　不幸にも戦死された
As to that...
I regret to inform you that he has fallen.
Fallen?
戦死？
Is this true?
それは誠か
Yes.
ああ　無念だ
It is deplorable.
狼藉者が我が領地に行った　隕石爆撃に巻き込まれて
He was struck by a meteor bombardment brutishly launched over my territory.
That is just not...
そのような事が
おかしい　爆撃の事は伝えてある　巻き込まれるはずは無い
Strange.
I informed him of the bombardment.
He should not have been caught in it.
Sir Trillram did all that could be asked of him as my guest.
トリルラン卿は食客として尽くしてくれた
それがこのような別れになるとは
I hoped to part with him under different circumstances.
Let us pray for our brave warrior's happiness in the next life.
勇敢な戦士の冥福を祈ろう
On that note, did any witness his end?
それで　トリルラン卿の最期を見た者はおるのか
どうすればいいんだ
What should I do?
I know the princess is alive, but I can't tell them.
アセイラム姫が無事だと分かったのに…
このままではいつか本当に暗殺されてしまう
Something has to be done, or she really will be killed.
Be quick with the repairs!
修理急げ　グズグズするな
Get cracking!
Argyre...
アルギュレ　頭が…
The head is damaged!
ご無事で　ブラド卿
I'm glad to see you unhurt, Sir Vlad.
You call this unhurt?
何が無事なものか
My very honor has been tarnished.
我が名誉は地に堕ちた
強い相手だったのですか
Was your opponent that powerful?
いいや　オレンジ色の小賢しい奴にバカにされただけだ
No.
I was played for a fool by that orange cur.
Why are you here?
ここで何をしている
Should you not be at the Count's side?
伯爵に付いていなくて良いのか
叱られました　出過ぎた事を言って
I was punished for speaking out of turn.
Out of turn?
出過ぎた事？
私にも出撃させて欲しいと
I asked to be sent into battle.
貴様も同じだな
You're all the same, I see.
地球人だ　小賢しい
Terrans.
Impudent curs.
Are you that eager to curry favor
through your deeds on the battlefield?
そんなに武勲を上げて取り立ててもらいたいか　つまらぬ奴め
Pathetic.
違います　私はただ…
No!
I just...
姫様の事が…
Her Highness...
つまらぬ
Pathetic.
なるほど　これでオートパイロット
Oh, I see.
This is the autopilot.
君達　名前は
What are your names?
N-Nina Klein.
ニーナ・クラインです
詰城祐太朗です
Tsumugi Yuutarou.
祭陽希咲っす
Matsuribi Kisaki.
Does this mean we'll be sent into battle?
もしかして私達　実戦に参加するんですか
No. These are just supplementary lessons.
まさか　ただの補習授業だよ
万一に備えてね
In case we ever run low on manpower.
Okay.
ういっす
備えるんだ
Just in case, huh?
君が敵カタフラクトを撃退したのですね　網文君
You repelled the enemy Cataphract,
Amifumi?
はい　マグバレッジ艦長
Yes, Captain Magbaredge.
Actually, my friend here came up with the operation.
ああ　いえ　作戦を立てたのは彼で
作戦？
Operation?
Say something.
ほら
作戦という程の物ではありませんが
"Operation" is a bit of an exaggeration.
You piloted that training unit, right?
あの練習機のパイロットは　あなたですか
はい　界塚伊奈帆です
I did.
I'm Kaizuka Inaho.
Kaizuka?
界塚…
Yes.
はい　界塚ユキ准尉は僕の姉です
Warrant Officer Kaizuka Yuki is my older sister.
よくやりました　伊奈帆君
Good work, Inaho.
君の働きで　多くの乗組員及び民間人の命が救われました
You saved the lives of many sailors and civilians.
お姉さんも鼻が高いでしょう
Your sister must be proud of you.
正規軍人であれば　賞賛章に推薦したい所です
If you were a regular combatant,
I'd nominate you for commendations.
賞賛章
Commendations?
勲章の事ですよ
Medals.
凄いじゃない　勲章だって
Isn't that cool?
We could get medals!
凄い…のかな
Is it?
そりゃ凄いでしょ　貰った人見た事無いもん
Of course it is!
I've never seen anybody with a medal.
それはずっと　実戦が無かったからだよ
That's 'cause it's been a long time since we've had any real fighting.
Instructor Marito!
鞠戸教官
教官？ここは学校じゃないぞ
Instructor?
We're not at school anymore.
My apologies, Lieutenant Marito.
すみませんでした　鞠戸大尉
It's gonna be raining medals soon, mark my words.
これからは勲章も珍しく無くなるぞ
Honor's about the only thing they can reward you with during a war.
戦時下だ　名誉くらいしか出せる褒美は無いからな
Dying for fame isn't so bad, really.
ま　名誉の為に死ぬのも悪くない
Surviving to live a wretched life sucks as well.
惨めに生き残るのも辛いからな
鞠戸大尉
Lieutenant Marito.
ちょっといいですか
Could you come here for a moment?
軍艦で開業かい　先生
You setting up shop here, Doc?
A man must work to eat, after all.
働かざる者食うべからず
Couldn't you leave those kids with their dreams for a little while longer, Lieutenant?
若者の夢を壊すのはあまり関心しませんね　大尉
飲んではいないようですね
You seem to be sober.
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
信用してくれて嬉しいぜ
I thought you might've been picking
on those kids because you were drunk.
酔って子供に絡んでるのかと思いました
Well, maybe I am drunk.
酔ってはいるかもな　己の運命って奴に
Drunk on my own sad fate.
「種子島レポート」の事ですか
You mean the Tanegashima Report?
The sins of the past haunt you forever.
犯した罪は魂にこびり付いていつまでも付き纏う
And sins that go unpunished are never atoned for.
ましてや裁かれない罪は死ぬまで許される事は無い
ヒュームレイさん
Humeray...
あなたに罪はありません　むしろあなたは彼の事を助けた
They are not your sins.
On the contrary, you saved him.
助けた…ね
Saved him, huh?
おいどうした
What's going on?
M-Message from Mars!
か…火星から　休戦の申し入れがあったそうです
They've announced an armistice!
愚蒙なる地球の民に告げる
Attention, foolish people of Earth.
Our great emperor,
Rayregalia Vers Rayvers,
我らが偉大なるヴァース帝国皇帝　レイレガリア・ヴァース・レイヴァース陛下は
地球連合政府に対する休戦を布告なさった
has extended an armistice
to the UE government.
Even as we feel intense shame in our common ancestry with you,
まともに通信出来ないのに　こんな海賊放送ばっかり
We hardly get any signal here.
Just these pirate broadcasts.
we hope that this act conveys to you, the deeply sinful people of Earth
Well, I guess this means
the war's on hold for now.
ま　とりあえず戦争はお休みって事か
who took the life of
Her Highness Princess Asseylum,
きっと騎士達の行き過ぎた行動を　お祖父様が止めようとしているのでしょう
I assume my grandfather is trying to curb the Knights' behavior.
the profound compassion of
His Imperial Majesty Rayregalia.
火星の皇帝が
The emperor of Mars?
What is this?
どういう事だ
It would appear His Imperial Majesty has declared an armistice to the UE.
レイレガリア皇帝が　連合政府に休戦の申し入れをされたとの事です
我々の頭を超えてか　軌道騎士に何の連絡も無くか
Over our heads?
Without so much as a word
to the Orbital Knights?
皇帝に進言せねば
I must offer my advice to the emperor.
謁見の間を使う　月面基地を呼べ
I will use the audience chamber.
Get the moon base on the line.
はっ
Understood.
では　隕石爆撃でやられたのでは無いのだな
So he was not killed in the bombardment?
No.
はい　ニロケラスは戦闘によって損傷　放棄された模様です
It would appear that the Nilokeras was
damaged in battle and then abandoned.
There is someone I wish to look into.
行動を調べたい者がいる
Infiltrate Castle Cruhteo and investigate.
引き続きクルーテオ城に潜入　調査せよ
Yes, my lord.
はっ
They opened hostilities without warning and stopped just as suddenly.
一方的に開戦して慌てて休戦　何かすっきりしませんね
It doesn't make any sense.
Maybe it means the enemy
isn't as monolithic as it seems.
敵も一枚岩では無いって事でしょうか
Any contact from the main force?
本隊との連絡は
No.
いえ　相変わらずジャミングがひどくて
They're still jamming us.
Where are you headed?
どちらへ行かれるのですか
To find the person responsible for this ship.
この船の責任者の元へ　私の正体を告げます
I shall reveal my identity to them.
Your Highness—
姫様
そして　私の無事をヴァースに伝えてもらいます
And then I will ask them to inform Vers of my safety.
Doing so will end this war.
そうすれば　この戦争は終わります
That's too dangerous!
危険です　皇帝陛下に伝わる前に反逆者が来ます
The rebels will be upon us before
His Majesty even hears about you!
And that is why this armistice
provides us with the perfect opportunity.
だからこそ　休戦状態の今が機会なのです
Don't underestimate them.
あいつらを甘く見ないで
There's no chance they'll just roll over
and accept the armistice.
大人しく休戦協定を守る連中じゃない
You'll get crushed like a bug.
握り潰されるだけ
But the longer this war drags on,
the more casualties there will be!
しかし　戦争が長引けばそれだけ犠牲者が増えます
You're free to have a death wish.
あなたが死にたいのは勝手だけど　巻き込まないで
Just keep it to yourself.
The enemy?
敵襲？
What about the armistice?
休戦中だって
I won't allow the fighting to end without having a chance to redeem my honor!
我が誇りを回復する機会も無いまま　終戦になっては困るのでな
Bastard.
野郎　リベンジしようってか
Back for round two, huh?
Lieutenant, where are you going?
大尉　どちらへ
All units, sortie! Intercept!
艦載機発進　迎撃せよ
艦長　CICに移動を
Captain, you should relocate to the Operations Room.
I'll be fine here.
大丈夫です　こちらで
話にならん
This is ridiculous!
What is His Majesty thinking?
何を考えておられるのだ陛下は　肉親を殺されたのだぞ
His own granddaughter was murdered!
調査団を組織せよ
Form an investigation squad.
As per His Majesty's orders, we will uncover all details of the princess' assassination!
陛下の仰せの通り姫暗殺の経緯を詳しく調査するのだ
Yes, my lord.
はっ
これで…　皇帝陛下に
This connects...
to His Majesty...
This is...
ここは…
Now, let us dance again!
さあ　この前の続きだ
En garde!
抜刀
Aldaniti Platoon, prepare for launch.
アルダニティ小隊　発進準備
Raising Elevator 2.
二番エレベーター　上昇
To all units: do not use HE rounds.
Engage using AP rounds!
各機　HE弾は使うな　AP弾で応戦しろ
Asshole!
野郎
Hold it!
待て
He's using us as a shield!
艦橋を盾に
なお君
Nao?
En garde.
抜刀
What do you think you're doing? Stand down!
何してるの　降りなさい
That goes double for you, Yuki. You're hurt.
ユキ姉こそ　負傷兵だろ
We don't have enough pilots!
パイロットが足りないの
なら僕が出たって同じだ
Then I might as well fight.
Have you seen my pajamas?
パジャマどこ
The patched-up ones.
アップリケの奴
Your Imperial Majesty...
皇帝陛下
Who are you?
誰だ
Slaine Troyard, if it pleases you.
スレイン・トロイヤードです
Slaine?
スレイン？
Oh. It has been some time, no?
おお　久しいな
It has indeed.
はい
And why are you here?
ここに　何の用だ
There is something I must tell you, Your Majesty.
皇帝陛下にお伝えしたい事があります
You see...
実は…
Princess Asselyum...
アセイラム姫は生きています
is alive.
I saw her with my own eyes.
僕はこの目で見ました
地球と戦争をしたいばかりに　アセイラム姫を殺そうとしたのは軌道騎士です
It was the Orbital Knights, thinking only of battle with Earth, who attempted to assassinate her.
But they failed.
でも　暗殺は失敗して
Princess Asseylum is alive
somewhere on Earth right now!
アセイラム姫は今　地球のどこかで生きています
You finally show yourself,
現れたな　我が宿敵よ
my nemesis.
A training unit?
練習機？
Could it be...
あれってもしかして…
Inaho?
伊奈帆
You think a tactical suit's
gonna keep you safe from that?!
タクティカルスーツで防げるかよ
There is no armor my blades cannot cut!
この刀に切れぬ鎧はない
一瞬で片を付ける
I'll end this in a flash!
Inaho!
伊奈帆さん
Nice!
Reactive armor.
リアクティブアーマー　爆薬でできた装甲板
Armor plates layered with explosives.
They were originally designed to detonate
and deflect incoming fire.
本来は爆発で敵の砲弾を跳ね返す物
Damn you!
おのれ
爆発で刀のプラズマを吹き飛ばしてるのか
He's using the blasts to disperse the blade's plasma?
Control, tilt the ship to one side.
コントロール　船を傾けてください
Mizusaki.
不見咲
Flood the ballast.
バラスト注水
Well dock hatch, open!
ウェルドック　ハッチ解放
Unhand me!
離せ
Good idea.
好都合だ
Backpack ejected.
バックパック　投棄良し
Bailing out.
ベイルアウト
What?
何っ
Inaho!
伊奈帆
何だ今の
What was that?
A steam explosion.
水蒸気爆発
The enormous heat energy in the blades instantly converted the ocean water to high-pressure steam,
あの刀の膨大な熱エネルギーが　海水を急激に蒸発させ
その高圧水蒸気の衝撃が　奴を破壊した
and the impact destroyed him.
Kaizuka Inaho.
界塚伊奈帆　学生とは思えませんね
Hard to believe he's a student.
ええ　意外に使える子ですね
Yes. He's surprisingly useful.
Mizusaki.
不見咲君　君がモテない理由を教えましょうか
Do I need to remind you why men don't like you?
素直な性格は好まれるのでは
Isn't honesty the best policy?
There's a difference between honest and rude.
君のは素直ではなく　遠慮がないと言うのです
Let's go pick up Inaho!
伊奈帆を回収に行こう
そなたの言う事が誠であれば　何と嘆かわしい
If what you say is true,
then the situation is indeed deplorable.
I beg of you, Your Majesty,
please stop this war without delay.
一刻も早くこの戦争を止めてください
And please rescue Princess Asseylum!
そして　アセイラム姫を救出してください
うむ　直ちに取り計らおう
I shall see to it at once.
Thank you very much, Your Majesty.
ありがとうございます　皇帝陛下
I shall take my leave.
それでは
It was just as you said, Count Saazbaum.
貴公の言った通りだな　ザーツバルム伯爵
地球人は信用なりません
No Terran can be trusted.
至る所にスパイが紛れ込んでおり　隙あらばヴァース転覆をと企んでおります
Their spies are everywhere,
constantly waiting for the opportunity
to overthrow Vers.
After the loss of your beloved princess,
your heart must be broken, Your Majesty.
大切な姫を失い　心を痛めておられる陛下を
No affront can be greater than their filthy lies!
空事で惑わそうなど言語道断
Your Majesty,
皇帝陛下　卑しき種族に　どうか正義の鉄槌を
I ask that you bring down the
hammer of justice upon that vile race!
ヴァース帝国皇帝　レイレガリア・ヴァース・レイヴァースの名において
I, Vers Emperor Rayregalia Vers Rayvers,
once again wave the flag of war.
改めて宣戦を布告する　地球を攻撃せよ
Attack Earth!
Those who would harm my own flesh and blood...
我が血族に仇なす者を
must burn!
焼き払え
Slaine Troyard.
スレイン・トロイヤード　我が大義に仇をなすか
You seek to undermine our cause.
皮肉だな
Isn't that ironic...
Dr. Troyard?
トロイヤード博士
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:つっちー   翻译:mam&低音子   校对:小可&zwx   时间轴:框子   压制:河蟹
rei
Zero
0　始まりにも　終わりにも　変わる光
hajimari ni mo
Both the beginning
owari ni mo
and the end
kawaru hikari
see the changing of light
shita ni muketa mama
Back when I decided
下に向けたまま　かざすのを止めた　あの時
kazasu no wo yameta ano toki
that I would stop fooling myself and others,
LP no saizu no awanai uso bakari narabete
all I did was pile lie upon lie,
ALD noah
LP no saizu no awanai uso bakari narabete
all I did was pile lie upon lie,
サイズの合わない　嘘ばかり並べて
見失い　自ら全てに　つまずいた
miushinai mizukara subete ni tsumazuita
with no chance to be comfortable with myself
earth terasu a to a
Shine on Earth
AS　照らす　影と栄
kurikaesu count
Count again
繰り返すcount　明日の零時のサイン
asu no reiji no sign
The sign of twelve in the morning
lie mo die
Lie and die
LIVE or DIE
mienai hikari no sen
Under the sunlight,
見えない　光の線
ochiru dake de
just from that,
文字だけで　生kill-場所捨てて
kuruu basho subete
everything goes mad
名前も居ない　そこに　答えを求めてても
namae mo nai soko ni
Even though I vainly seek answers
kotae wo motometetemo
from that kind of nameless place,
風にとかした　命のRain　投げ捨てない
kaze ni tokashita inochi no rei
I won't throw away my soul
nagesutenai
as it is carried on the wind
kakedashi no namida
These are my first tears
駆け出しのナミダ
kitai mo yami no owari mo iranai
I don't need expectations or an end to the darkness
期待も闇も終わりもいらない
zero ni nareba
When all goes back to zero,
ゼロになれば　裸足のphrase-1
hadashi no brave one
I walk barefoot, and with courage